Guide to the Benjamin Andrews collection on home economics, 1879-1958.
Andrews, Benjamin collection on home economics
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Benjamin Andrews collection on home economics, 1879-1958.
1475
Benjamin R.(Benjamin Richard), Andrews b. 1877
1 cubic ft.
Correspondence and subject files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes two letters to Andrews from Louis C. Karpinski (Cornell University Class of 1901); a draft of PIONEERING IN HOME ECONOMICS by Andrews, primarily concerning the development of home economics at Columbia, with a brief section on the College of Home Economics at Cornell University; and twelve photographs of black housing in Missouri around 1940. Publications and other writings on home economics, home economics leaders, domestic science, and extension services authored by the government, universities and individuals.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University, Class of 1901. Professor of household economics, Columbia University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes two letters to Andrews from Louis C. Karpinski (Cornell University Class of 1901); a draft of PIONEERING IN HOME ECONOMICS by Andrews, primarily concerning the development of home economics at Columbia, with a brief section on the College of Home Economics at Cornell University; and twelve photographs of black housing in Missouri around 1940. Publications and other writings on home economics, home economics leaders, domestic science, and extension services authored by the government, universities and individuals.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Benjamin R.(Benjamin Richard), Andrews b. 1877.; Karpinski, Louis Charles, 1879-1956.; Columbia University.Teachers College.School of Household Arts.; New York State College of Home Economics.
Subjects:
Afro-Americans--Housing.; Blacks--Missouri.; Home economics--Study and teaching.; Home economics--History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records, #6578.
CONTAINER LIST
- Photographs, black housing in Missouri, circa 1940 (Box 1)
- Letters from Louis C. Karpinski (Cornell University, Class of 1901), 1951, 1953 (Box 1)
- Pioneering in Home Economics by Benjamin Andrews, 1958 (Box 1)
- Lists (Box 2)
- History of Home Economics - Letters to Benjamin Andrews, 1952 (Box 2)
- Women's Library, 1904-1912 (Box 2)
- Highlights of Historical Interest of AHEA found in Bulletins, 1912-1939 (Box 2)
- Health-Social Economics (Box 2)
- Education for Women, 1879, 1905-1913 (Box 2)
- Association of Teachers of Domestic Subjects-England, 1910-1918 (Box 2)
- Family Life-Bulletins from Related Organizations, 1879, 1902-1938 (Box 2)
- Cuban American Conference on Home Economics, 1943-1944 (Box 2)
- History of Nutrition, Todhunter, 1948-1951 (Box 2)
- National Kitchens and National Health, 1917-1919 (Box 2)
- Community Kitchens, 1918-1920 (Box 2)
- The Philadelphia Cooking School (Box 2)
- Domestic Service History, 1898-1910, 1939 (Box 2)
- Household Administration, 1908-1916 (Box 2)
- U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1917-1921 (Box 2)
- University of California, 1918-1919 (Box 2)
- Florida State College, 1917-1919 (Box 2)
- Kansas State, 1917-1918 (Box 2)
- Michigan Agricultural College, 1914-1918 (Box 3)
- University of Minnesota, 1911-1918 (Box 3)
- University of Missouri, 1920 (Box 3)
- Montana State, 1915-1919 (Box 3)
- New York State, Cornell, 1919 (Box 3)
- North Dakota Agricultural College, 1914, 1918 (Box 3)
- Penn State College, 1915-1918 (Box 3)
- University of Tennessee, 1916-1918 (Box 3)
- University of Vermont, 1919 (Box 3)
- University of Wisconsin, 1916-1919 (Box 3)
- Xenophon's Oeconomicus or The Management of a Farm and Household 445-355 B.C. (Box 3)
- World Federation of Education Associations, Home Economics section, 1939-1941 (Box 3)
- Early Home Economics educators (Box 3)
- Anna Garlin Spencer (Box 3)
- Wilbur O. Atwater (Box 3)
- Sarah Louise Arnold (Box 3)
- Helen Campbell (Box 3)
- Mary Lyon (Box 3)
- Advisory Council of the Herald Tribune Home Institute (Box 3)
- Anna Barrows (Box 3)
- Effie Raitt (Box 3)
- The School of Housekeeping, 1900 (Box 3)
- Choice Receipts by Maria Parloa, 1897 (Box 3)
- The Whys of Cooking by Janet McKenzie Hill, 1916 (Box 3)
- Helen Kinne (Box 3)
- Annie Godfrey Dewey (Box 3)
- Grace H. Dodge (Box 3)
- Catherine Beecher (Box 4)
- The New England Kitchen (Box 4)
- Emma Willard (Box 4)
- Mary Wollstonecraft, 1912 (Box 4)
- International Committee on the Teaching of Home Economics (AHEA), 1914-1920 (Box 4)
- Edward L. Youmans (Box 4)
- Alice Ravenhill (Box 4)
- News articles of leaders in home economics (Box 4)
- Smoot Bill, 1913 (Box 4)
- Count Rumford history, 2 folders (Box 4)
- Paul DeVuyst, international home education (Box 4)
- National Organization of High School Home Economics Clubs, 1944 (Box 4)